Okay, now I don't mean to confuse you,
but I have now quit VS Code just to
start fresh. And I brought up cursor
again. It looks so similar. It's like,
okay, all right. There's still the
sidebar on the right. This is instant.
I'm back in instant again because look
what I want to do is I'm in the the
project subdirectory. So if you were
when you open up instant, you're inside
instant. I've done cd dot dot and I'm
back up in the projects subdirectory. If
I do pwd, you can see I'm in my projects
directory. And there's now a new folder
called Cananban that has everything that
GitHub Copilot just built. And I'm going
to change that name. I'm going to do mv
move, which is like rename canban. And
I'm going to change it to being like
copilot copilot_ban
or whatever you want, but just to keep a
record of it. But that's now removed
camban altogether because now we're
going to go in and do this all over
again. And so do you remember the next
command I'm going to run? It's going to
be get clone and then that that you
could take from the course resources or
or from my my GitHub cam.git. I run that
and we've now got ourselves a fresh
canban folder again just with the one
file which is our agents.md.
Okay, it is time for the next on our
list, OpenAI's codeex. And here we are
on the Codeex web page from OpenAI
telling us all about Codeex. And you'll
see that Codeex is first and foremost
one of these CLI kinds of tools like
Claude Code. And next week is when we're
going to be getting deep into CLI tools,
but and it even tells you how to get
started with like a CLI, a command, and
it shows you screenshots of it looking
looking like one of these kinds of
interfaces that we will get to in time.
But it turns out that there is another
way that you can use codeex which is
again as another VS Code extension.
Codeex is a VS Code extension too. And
for this week since we're all about
using the IDE that's how we'll do it. So
I'm going to see you back over in VS
Code. Can you launch that again, please?
I'll see you there. So after you launch
VS Code, you should see a screen. Maybe
a welcome screen. Maybe it's a screen
like this. Whatever it is, you should be
able to press control shiftx on a PC or
commandshiftx on a Mac. It's also going
to be the view menu. And then it is
extensions. And up comes the extensions
like this. And right now it's still got
GitHub Copilot selected cuz that's the
last search I did. I'm going to delete
that. And you never guess what I'm going
to search for. I'm going to search for
Codeex. And uh there it is right up at
the top here. Of course, I'm already
installed because I've used it. Codeex
OpenAI's coding assistant. It's from
OpenAI with that tick to show you that
it's the real deal. And it's had for me
three and a bit million downloads for
you, probably a lot more. This is it.
This is Codeex. You should press
install. Mine's already installed, so I
don't have that. Once you've done that,
you will have Codeex on your system.
Okay? And it's possible you might need
to to quit VS Code and bring it back up
again. But once you have the way that
you'll know that you have Codeex
installed in VS Code is because you'll
have this little symbol over here, a
little codec symbol. What a treat. You
press that and up comes a sidebar. It's
on the left side rather than the right
side. So, so you know something's
different. Uh and here we are in Codeex.
Uh so, uh are you ready? The first thing
I'm going to do is I'm going to go to
the file new window box and I need to re
I'm going to do open and I'm going to go
into projects and I'm going to open
canban. Click into it and press open.
And here it is with the single
agents.mmd
file. And I'm going to make this bigger.
And confusingly,
you see what's going on here?
Confusingly, we have copilot over here
on the right. X out of that. We don't
want that. Go away copilot. We're done
with you. You're you're you're dead to
us. We've moved on. We're on to codeex.
We We can now press the codeex button
over here to open up the codeex screen
right here and get to it. And I'm going
to make it a bit bigger with command
plus. There we go. And also I'm going to
drag this to the right so we have a
little bit more space. Uh, and I need to
mention that you can go to the you need
to go to the settings right here. And
this is where you would log in with your
OpenAI account. And now Codex is I
believe as far as I know only a paid uh
model approach. Actually before I say
that maybe just click here to see uh you
could you could take a look at this and
see whether if you don't have uh chatgbt
account whether you're able to choose
any other models but I do believe that
you need to have an open AI account at
least you do as of now like a like a
subscription plan a chat GPT uh plan not
not an open AI account. Um, and so
that's that's what you would need to do.
And you can, of course, skip this one.
It's going to be so much the same as all
the others. I just want to show you the
tooling. It's not important that you
have accounts for all these different
platforms if you don't wish to, but but
I do. And that is the one that we are
going to use right now. So, we can see
we've got some drop downs here. There's
there's uh agent full access is what I
have selected. Actually, I think it was
original and agent and I moved it to
agent full access which is which is like
again the the the YOLO mode. Um then
there's choosing the model. So GPT 5.2
codeex for me right now is the the
strongest most powerful model that we've
got. You you probably remember this from
looking at my my screenshot of
artificial analysis. But no doubt by the
time that you're doing this there'll be
new models. There'll be more. And so you
should use what whatever whatever you
wish. if you're a chat GPT subscriber.
And over here is the reasoning effort.
This is where you can control um how how
deeply it thinks using that that trick
that we discussed. Uh and making it
higher will get you better outcomes,
higher quality, but it will take longer.
And it's not always better. Sometimes
you find that if you make it think too
much, then it can overthink. it can kind
of agonize over stuff in a way that that
feels counterproductive, like it should
have just gone for it. So, it's not
always the case that more thinking leads
to better outcomes. It depends a bit on
the project and and there's there's a
sort of art and science to that. But all
things considered, I'm going to have
this on high. I think that's the right
one for me now. All right. And with
that, there isn't there isn't a plan
mode, but but we've told it that that we
want it in the in agents.mmd to do its
planning first. So, I'm just going to
say please go ahead. Uh, it also knows
to look for an agents.m MD. So, it
should already understand. Look, it's
identifying documentation to read. It's
reading agents.m MD and it's thinking
and it's now going to do its thing. And
so, uh, I'm going to let it, uh, work
for a bit and I will see you in a
minute. Okay. Well, that's cool. It
lasted a lot longer than any of the
others so far. That was a good 15
minutes that have gone by. I know it was
just a second for you, but it was 15
minutes for me. And it's been going.
It's been doing tons of stuff. I also
noticed down here that you can see the
context window usage right here, just as
we did with cursor at the beginning. 16%
used uh 42,000 out of 258,000 tokens
used. Okay. And it tells us, if we have
a look, it's given us a little report
here. It says that the dev server is is
running launched via mpm rundev. Uh so
it's it's running. It tells me how I can
stop it if I wish to. And uh it's
telling me everything that it's changed,
including 74 different files. That's a
lot of work. Okay, it's time for us to
to try this out. All right, so we're
going to go to localhost 3000. And wow.
Okay, well, it definitely looks cool. Uh
single board canban studio. It's got a
cool name. Focus. One board, five
columns, zero clutter.
Uh all right. And here we go. Here are
the different things. So, let's let's
see if the functionality works. Uh, and
I I love the what what it's got here.
Uh, move that over here. And there it
goes. Can we can we rearrange? Yes, we
can rearrange. Can we remove? Yes, we
can remove. Can we rename in progress to
Wow. And look at that. It updates there.
Okay. Okay. I got to hand it to it. This
This is pretty amazing. This This is
great. Definitely best so far. It looks
beautiful. It's uh yeah, really nice.
And uh yeah, we we should of course try
uh uh impressed.
I am.
Uh there we go. There we go. Well, I'm
blown away by that. This is as this is
an example again of what they call zero
shot. This is just we we we gave it the
instructions. We let it be. This is the
outcome. It didn't even ask any
questions. It just built this just like
that. And I know what you're thinking.
You're thinking, "Okay, Ed, but look,
you've you've raced through all of this.
You haven't you haven't shown us how how
to write the code, how the how it works,
like like how do you build an XJS app to
do all of this? So, so how can I check
if it's if it's done a good job?" Well,
look, I've got a secret for you here,
and it's just you keep this between you
and me, if that's okay. Uh, the secret
is I don't know how to write this kind
of front-end code either. I'm a lousy
React developer. I've built some React
screens before, but I'm really bad at
them. They look horrible. uh as front-
end developers on my team will tell you
uh but uh but but uh this this is doable
even if you don't know how to write
front-end code that's the amazing thing
you can act like the manager you can
give feedback I mean I knew that mpm
rundev was how to bring up the server
but you can ask it that as well and
we'll talk tomorrow and and throughout
the next few weeks about the ways in
which you can operate handinhand with
with a collaborator like this to get the
best out of both. But the bottom line is
uh amazingly particularly actually with
front-end stuff, you don't need to have
a detailed understanding of the
technology to be able to build things
like this. Now, of course, the the
devil's in the detail and and and it's
fine for a toy project like this, but
things get a lot more complicated when
you have a much bigger system and when
you have much more advanced uh
requirements. And that's why this is
still day three of a 3-week course and
we've got lots still to go. But I gotta
say this, I I think this is really
awesome.